<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<Recipes>


	<Recipe>
		<Name>Raja Jingla in coconut milk</Name>
		<Description>In a little vegetable oil soften thinly sliced red & green bell…</Description>
		<Picture>rajajinglaincoconutmilk</Picture>
		<Thumbnail>RajaJinglaincoconutmilk</Thumbnail>
		<SecondPicture>Rajajinglaincoconutmilk</SecondPicture>
		<Instructions>
		In a little vegetable oil soften thinly sliced red & green bell peppers together with Surti Masala, on low heat for 5mins, in a covered pan to retain the moisture. Mix ~600g of tiger / king prawns, warm though for 4-5 mins, fold in 2-3 tablespoons of coconut milk or single cream. Rest for 5 minutes. Garnish with chopped coriander and serve with a little basmati rice and green leaf salad. Delicious! 
		</Instructions>
	</Recipe>


	<Recipe>
		<Name>Mutter Butternut Squash</Name>
		<Description>Mix-in Jeera Masala to ~800g of diced (1cm cubes) butternut-squash…</Description>
		<Picture>MutterButternutSquash</Picture>
		<Thumbnail>MutterButternutSquash</Thumbnail>
		<SecondPicture>MutterButternutSquash</SecondPicture>
		<Instructions>
		Mix-in Jeera Masala to ~800g of diced (1cm cubes) butternut-squash, and a hand full of peas, no need to add anything else, it's all in the port. Cook for ~20-25 minutes at low heat in a covered pan to retain the moisture. Rest for 5 mins. Optional, fold-in yoghurt for saucy dish. Serve with a little rice and green leaf onion salad. Enjoy!
		</Instructions>
	</Recipe>

	<Recipe>
		<Name>Aromatic Roast Murgh</Name>
		<Description>Mix in Methi or Garam Masala to ~600g of skinned drum sticks in a…</Description>
		<Picture>AromaticRoastMurgh</Picture>
		<Thumbnail>AromaticRoastMurgh</Thumbnail>
		<SecondPicture>AromaticRoastMurgh</SecondPicture>
		<Instructions>
		Mix in Methi or Garam Masala to ~600g of skinned drum sticks in a baking tray. No need to add any oil. Cover with foil and bake at 190C for 25-30 minutes. Garnish with chopped coriander and match-sticks fo fresh ginger. Serve as an appetiser on a bed of mixed green salad with a few slithers of red onion or as main with rice. The end result will be an aromatic flavoursome dish fit for a Raja!
		</Instructions>
	</Recipe>

	<Recipe>
		<Name>Murg Masala with summer tomatoes</Name>
		<Description>Soften a finely chopped medium onion in a little vegetable…</Description>
		<Picture>MurgMasalawithsummertomatoes</Picture>
		<Thumbnail>MurgMasalawithsummertomatoes</Thumbnail>
		<SecondPicture>MurgMasalawithsummertomatoes</SecondPicture>
		<Instructions>
		Soften a finely chopped medium onion in a little vegetable oil with a tablespoon of tomato puree. Add ~600g of chicken, mix in Surti masala, no need to add anything else. Cook for 25 minutes at low heat in a covered pan to retain the moisture. Fold in a tablespoon of single cream or yoghurt. Serve with a little rice and green leaf onion salad. Enjoy!
		</Instructions>
	</Recipe>


	<Recipe>
		<Name>Roast Masala Aloo</Name>
		<Description>Mix in Jeera or Garam masala to ~800g parboiled potatoes…</Description>
		<Picture>RoastMasalaAloo</Picture>
		<Thumbnail>RoastMasalaAloo</Thumbnail>
		<SecondPicture>RoastMasalaAloo</SecondPicture>
		<Instructions>
		Mix in Jeera or Garam masala to ~800g parboiled potatoes, add a little olive oil + a few knobs of butter, mix thoroughly till surfaces are coated and fluffy. Roast at 180-190C for 30 minutes. Serve with Surti chicken and a little rice with green leaf onion salad. Enjoy!
		</Instructions>
	</Recipe>


	<Recipe>
		<Name>Pan Fried Salmon Masala</Name>
		<Description>Use a teaspoon of Surti or Machi Masala to coat a medium…</Description>
		<Picture>PanFriedSalmonMasala</Picture>
		<Thumbnail>PanFriedSalmonMasala</Thumbnail>
		<SecondPicture>PanFriedSalmonMasala</SecondPicture>
		<Instructions>
		Use a teaspoon of Surti or Machi Masala to coat a medium sized fillet of salmon. Evenly spread the masala using the back of the teaspoon. Pan fry on low heat in a drop of olive oil. Cook each side for 6-7 minutes, only turn once, start cooking with the upper surface first. Rest for 2-3 minutes. Serve with green beans, mustard mash potatoe / little leaf salad. Enjoy!
		</Instructions>
	</Recipe>

	<Recipe>
		<Name>Quorn Masala</Name>
		<Description>Mix Garam masala with ~700g of Quorn chunks and 2 tablespoons…</Description>
		<Picture>QuornMasala</Picture>
		<Thumbnail>QuornMasala</Thumbnail>
		<SecondPicture>QuornMasala</SecondPicture>
		<Instructions>
		Mix Garam masala with ~700g of Quorn chunks and 2 tablespoons of yoghurt. Cook on low heat in a covered pan to retain the moisture, for 20 minutes. Add a tablespoon of water to make it soupy. Rest for 5 minutes. Garnish with coriander, serve with a little rice and green leaf onion salad. Quorn is equally delicious with Jeera, Surti, or Methi Masala. Enjoy!
		</Instructions>
	</Recipe>


	<Recipe>
		<Name>Fiery lamb sheek kebabs</Name>
		<Description>Mix Sheek kebab with ~600g of lean minced lamb using a fork…</Description>
		<Picture>Fierylambsheekkebabs</Picture>
		<Thumbnail>Fierylambsheekkebabs</Thumbnail>
		<SecondPicture>Fierylambsheekkebabs</SecondPicture>
		<Instructions>
		Mix Sheek kebab with ~600g of lean minced lamb using a fork, pat it on to 8 metal or wetted bamboo shewers. There is no need to add anything else. Refrigerate for 20 minutes so the mince firms up. BBQ or grill. Garnish with coriander. Serve with a green leaf onion salad and a wedge of lemon. The perfect appetiser.</Instructions>
	</Recipe>


	<Recipe>
		<Name>Steamed masala aloo</Name>
		<Description>Mix Garam masala with ~600g of sliced potato, and a tablespoon of…</Description>
		<Picture>Steamedmasalaaloo</Picture>
		<Thumbnail>Steamedmasalaaloo</Thumbnail>
		<SecondPicture>Steamedmasalaaloo</SecondPicture>
		<Instructions>
		Mix Garam masala with ~600g of sliced potato, and a tablespoon of water. There is no need to add anything else. Arrange in a deep dish so there are lots of air pockets, cover with foil to retain moisture and bake in the oven at 190C for 30 minutes. Garnish with coriander and serve with naan bread & green leaf salad. Works equally well with Jeera and Methi masala too. Enjoy!
		</Instructions>
	</Recipe>
	
	<Recipe>
		<Name>Fiery lamb burgers</Name>
		<Description>Mix Sheek Kebab masala with ~600g of lean minced lamb…</Description>
		<Picture>Fierylambburgers</Picture>
		<Thumbnail>Fierylambburgers</Thumbnail>
		<SecondPicture>Fierylambburgers</SecondPicture>
		<Instructions>
		Mix Sheek Kebab masala with ~600g of lean minced lamb, using forks to stop warming the meat up, form into 8-10 burgers. There is no need to add anything else as all the work of blending over 25 fresh herbs & spices is already provided. Refrigerate for 20 minutes so the mince firms up. BBQ or grill, garnish with coriander and serve with a green leaf onion salad. It's a perfect appetiser. Enjoy!
		</Instructions>
	</Recipe>
	
	<Recipe>
		<Name>Surti murg with coconut milk</Name>
		<Description>Mix Surti masala with ~600g of diced chicken…</Description>
		<Picture>Surtimurgwithcoconutmilk</Picture>
		<Thumbnail>Surtimurgwithcoconutmilk</Thumbnail>
		<SecondPicture>Surtimurgwithcoconutmilk</SecondPicture>
		<Instructions>
		Mix Surti masala with ~600g of diced chicken (try out chicken thighs), cook on low heat for 20 minutes in a covered pan to retain moisture. Fold in a tablespoon of coconut milk or alternatively single cream. There is no need to precook the chicken or add anything else. Garnish with coriander and serve with rice and green leaf onion salad. It's a perfect meal. Enjoy!
		</Instructions>
	</Recipe>
	

	<Recipe>
		<Name>Mumbai Spaghetti Jingla</Name>
		<Description>Mix in Machi masala with ~600g of tiger / king prawns…</Description>
		<Picture>MumbaiSpaghettiJingla</Picture>
		<Thumbnail>MumbaiSpaghettiJingla</Thumbnail>
		<SecondPicture>MumbaiSpaghettiJingla</SecondPicture>
		<Instructions>
		Mix in Machi masala with ~600g of tiger / king prawns, warm though for 4-5 minutes and fold in 400g of cooked spaghetti. Rest for 5 minutes. Garnish with chopped coriander and serve with a little rice and green leaf salad. Full of flavour bringing a dull pasta to life. Delicious!
		</Instructions>
	</Recipe>
	
	
	<Recipe>
		<Name>Aromatic Baroda Murg</Name>
		<Description>Mix garam or Methi masala with 2-3 tablespoons of natural…</Description>
		<Picture>AromaticBarodaMurg</Picture>
		<Thumbnail>AromaticBarodaMurg</Thumbnail>
		<SecondPicture>AromaticBarodaMurg</SecondPicture>
		<Instructions>
		Mix garam or Methi masala with 2-3 tablespoons of natural yoghurt and add to ~600g of diced chicken (try out chicken thighs). For a deeper infusion of flavour marinate for 30 minutes or in the fridge overnight. Cook on low heat for 20 minutes in a covered pan to retain moisture. There's no need to precook the chicken or add anything else. Garnish with coriander and serve with rice and green leaf onion salad. It's a perfect healthy meal. Enjoy!
		</Instructions>
	</Recipe>
	
	
	<Recipe>
		<Name>Aromatic Jeera Murg</Name>
		<Description>Mix Jeera masala with 1 tablespoon of natural yoghurt and…</Description>
		<Picture>AromaticJeeraMurg</Picture>
		<Thumbnail>AromaticJeeraMurg</Thumbnail>
		<SecondPicture>AromaticJeeraMurg</SecondPicture>
		<Instructions>
		Mix Jeera masala with 1 tablespoon of natural yoghurt and add to ~600g of diced chicken (try out chicken thighs), and leave to marinate for 30 minutes. Cook on low heat for 20 minutes in a covered pan to retain moisture. There's no need to precook the chicken or add anything else. Garnish with coriander, give a good squeeze of lemon, serve with rice and a green leaf onion salad. Absolutely delicious, Enjoy!
		</Instructions>
	</Recipe>
	
	
	<Recipe>
		<Name>Mumbai Pita</Name>
		<Description>Apply a tea spoon of Surti or Garam  masala to the upper surface of a…</Description>
		<Picture>MumbaiPita</Picture>
		<Thumbnail>MumbaiPita</Thumbnail>
		<SecondPicture>MumbaiPita</SecondPicture>
		<Instructions>
		Apply a tea spoon of Surti or Garam  masala to the upper surface of a pita bread. Top with sliced tomato, onion and a few leaves of basil and sprinkle with grated mild cheese. Season with cracked black pepper and sea salt. Grill for 5 mins. Healthy, tasty, quick snack. Enjoy!
		</Instructions>
	</Recipe>
	

	<Recipe>
		<Name>Aromatic Roast Murg</Name>
		<Description>Mix methi masala with 800g of skinless, scored, drum sticks. For a…</Description>
		<Picture>AromaticRoastMurg</Picture>
		<Thumbnail>AromaticRoastMurg</Thumbnail>
		<SecondPicture>AromaticRoastMurg</SecondPicture>
		<Instructions>
		Mix methi masala with 800g of skinless, scored, drum sticks. For a deep infusion of flavour marinate for 30 minutes or overnight. Cover with foil and cook in the oven for 50-60 minutes. Garnish with freshly chopped coriander and give a good squeeze of lemon. Serve on a bed of green leaf onion salad. Perfect appetiser and a party dish. Simple & easy. Enjoy!
		</Instructions>
	</Recipe>
	
	
	<Recipe>
		<Name>Aromatic Basmati</Name>
		<Description>To make an aromatic fluffy rice use one to two spoons of Jeera…</Description>
		<Picture>AromaticBasmati</Picture>
		<Thumbnail>AromaticBasmati</Thumbnail>
		<SecondPicture>AromaticBasmati</SecondPicture>
		<Instructions>
		To make an aromatic fluffy rice use one to two spoons of Jeera (you can also use Garam or Surti) per 2 cups of rice. Add to a lidded pan sufficient water so the rice is submerged under 2.5 - 3cm of water. Bring to boil and let it simmer on low heat to retain moisture. After 10-12 minutes the water will have been absorbed and fork the surface and add a knob of butter. Leave to rest and cook through own residual heat. Surti and Garam work equally well.
		</Instructions>
	</Recipe>
	
	
	<Recipe>
		<Name>Guji Gobi Mutter</Name>
		<Description>Mix in Jeera or Grama masala to little florets of 1 large cauliflower…</Description>
		<Picture>GujiGobiMutter</Picture>
		<Thumbnail>GujiGobiMutter</Thumbnail>
		<SecondPicture>GujiGobiMutter</SecondPicture>
		<Instructions>
		Mix in Jeera or Grama masala to little florets of 1 large cauliflower, add a hand full of frozen petite peas and a tablespoon of water. Cook in a lidded pan on low heat for 12-15 minutes till soft but crunchy to the bite. Rest for 5 mins. Garnish with freshly chopped coriander and a squeeze of lemon for an extra dimension. Enjoy!
		</Instructions>
	</Recipe>
	
	
	<Recipe>
		<Name>Zesty Machi Scallops Pasta</Name>
		<Description>Mix in Machi masala to ~300g of scallops, cook through on…</Description>
		<Picture>ZestyMachiScallopsPasta</Picture>
		<Thumbnail>ZestyMachiScallopsPasta</Thumbnail>
		<SecondPicture>ZestyMachiScallopsPasta</SecondPicture>
		<Instructions>
		Mix in Machi masala to ~300g of scallops, cook through on low heat for 4-5 minutes. Put aside to rest. Cook 200g of pasta. Add the masala scallops. Gently fold in a generous handful of chopped coriander, the zest and juice of a lemon, a large lemon. Don't be shy with the coriander and lemon juice as these bring out the tantalising flavours of the whole dish. Enjoy!
		</Instructions>
	</Recipe>
	

	<Recipe>
		<Name>Guji Quorn</Name>
		<Description>Mix Surti masale with ~700g of Quorn chunks, a tablespoon of…</Description>
		<Picture>GujiQuorn</Picture>
		<Thumbnail>GujiQuorn</Thumbnail>
		<SecondPicture>GujiQuorn</SecondPicture>
		<Instructions>
		Mix Surti masale with ~700g of Quorn chunks, a tablespoon of tomato puree and half a cup of water. Cook on low heat in a covered pan to retain the moisture for 20 minutes. Rest for 5 minutes. Garnish with coriander, serve with a little rice and green leaf onion salad. Enjoy!
		</Instructions>
	</Recipe>
	
	
	<Recipe>
		<Name>Surti Thai Noodle</Name>
		<Description>Add 200g of noodles into boiling water, cook for 4-5 mins…</Description>
		<Picture>SurtiThaiNoodle</Picture>
		<Thumbnail>SurtiThaiNoodle</Thumbnail>
		<SecondPicture>SurtiThaiNoodle</SecondPicture>
		<Instructions>
		Add 200g of noodles into boiling water, cook for 4-5 mins, drain and mix in 2-3 teaspoons of Surti masala. Garnish with coriander, serve as a side dish. It's easy, quick and delicious. Enjoy!
		</Instructions>
	</Recipe>
	
	
	<Recipe>
		<Name>Goan Aromatic Moules</Name>
		<Description>Add 800g of fresh mussels (discard open ones) into a deep pan…</Description>
		<Picture>GoanAromaticMoules</Picture>
		<Thumbnail>GoanAromaticMoules</Thumbnail>
		<SecondPicture>GoanAromaticMoules</SecondPicture>
		<Instructions>
		Add 800g of fresh mussels (discard open ones) into a deep pan with half a glass of white wine, 4 crushed garlic cloves, cracked back pepper, pinch of salt, knob of butter, glug of virgin olive oil, 2 teaspoons of Machi/Methi/Surti masala. Cover the pan with a tight lid, gently bring to a simmer, cook for 10-12 mins. Garnish with a generous helping of coriander and a good squeeze of lemon. Serve with ciabatta. Simple & easy. Enjoy!
		</Instructions>
	</Recipe>
	
	
	<Recipe>
		<Name>Zingy Bhajia Squid Rings</Name>
		<Description>Add 400g of squid rings into the freshly prepared Bipin's…</Description>
		<Picture>ZingyBhajiaSquidRings</Picture>
		<Thumbnail>ZingyBhajiaSquidRings</Thumbnail>
		<SecondPicture>ZingyBhajiaSquidRings</SecondPicture>
		<Instructions>
		Add 400g of squid rings into the freshly prepared Bipin's bhajia blend, thoroughly mix and fry for 2-3 minutes. Garnish with a generous helping of coriander and a good squeeze of lemon. Alternatively, try using a straight forward simple egg-flour batter with a teaspoon of Machi or Methi masala mixed in. It's an ideal appetiser with a difference and it's simple & easy. Enjoy!
		</Instructions>
	</Recipe>			
</Recipes>